Guide to the Patrick Daughton Papers AIA.055
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Patrick Daughton Papers
1881-2008
1969-1998
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Daughton, Patrick
Prendiville, Sean
AIA.055
14 Linear Feet in 18 boxes
The Patrick Daughton Collection documents activities of the San Francisco and Northern California Irish Republican Clubs (IRC). The collection contains correspondence between local IRC offices and the National office in New York as well as clubs in St. Paul, MN, Chicago, Boston and Philadelphia. Leaflets and clippings produced in coalition with other Irish and non-Irish groups for events such as Prince Charles' and Queen Elizabeth's visits, national and regional newsletters, and financial records are included in the collection. Material on other organizations such as the Institute for Celtic Studies in St. Paul, Minnesota, Irish National Caucus, and Noraid, Irish American Action Association, a group in San Francisco formed from a split from Noraid and the local Na Fianna Slua is also included. A significant collection of posters complementing the manuscript material completes the collection.
Scope and Contents
The Patrick Daughton Collection documents activities of the San Francisco and Northern California Irish Republican Clubs (IRC). The collection contains correspondence between local IRC offices and the National office in New York as well as Clubs in St. Paul, MN, Chicago, Boston and Philadelphia. Leaflets and clippings produced in coalition with other Irish and non-Irish groups for events such as Prince Charles' and Queen Elizabeth's visits, national and regional newsletters, and financial records are found in the collection. Material on other organizations such as Institute for Celtic Studies in St. Paul, Minnesota, Irish National Caucus and Noraid, Irish American Action Association, a group in San Francisco formed from a split from Noraid and the local Na Fianna Slua is also included. A significant collection of posters complementing the manuscript material completes the collection.
Series I. General Files includes files on individuals, organizations and various topics related to Irish American activities and responses to happenings in Northern Ireland. Also included is material on cultural events and organizations in the Northern Californian region.
Series II. Irish Republican Clubs contains files on various Irish Republican Clubs in Northern California and across the United States. Several folders document activities and work of the national IRC of North America. Publications put out by the IRC are included in this series.
Series III. Publications consists of partial runs of several publications and newsletters organized alphabetically. Also included are newspaper clippings organized by subject and a small set of articles and partial issues from historical newspapers.
The Poster series, Series IV. consists of over 50 posters. The poster collection came with detailed annotations and notes for many of the items and this information has been preserved in the folder descriptions. The original groupings of posters has been maintained. While not all posters are listed at the item level, item counts are given for each category. A few other posters from the collection are also included in this series.
Series V. Ephemera and Nonprint includes banners, raffle tickets, photographs, postcards and three 45 records.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Separated Materials
Sheet music was removed and put in the Archives of Irish America Vertical File Collection (AIA 013).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The material was donated to the Archives of Irish America by the Daughton family in California with the assistance of Sean Prendiville in 2009. The accession number associated with this gift is 2009.055.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Missing Title
Sean Prendiville Collection AIA 005
Frank Durkan Papers AIA 008
George Harrison Papers AIA 009
Irish Immigration Reform Movement Records AIA 016
Biographical Note
Patrick Daughton and Barbara Havenar were active members of the Helena Molony Irish Republic Club in Berekely, California in the 1970s. After the Irish Republican Clubs disbanded Patrick devoted his energies to supporting public education, after school programs, and art programs for young people. When Patrick died in 2008 his wife Barbara donated his files to the Archives of Irish America.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into five series.
Missing Title
Series I. General Files: Subjects and Organizations, 1956-2007
Series II. Irish Republican Clubs, 1969-1988
Series III. Publications, 1881-1998
Series IV. Posters, 1972-1998
Series V. Ephemera and Nonprint, 1966-1995
Ireland -- Politics and government -- 20th century.; Irish Americans |z California.; Irish Americans -- Social life and customs.; Irish Americans -- Politics and government.; Peace movements -- Northern Ireland; Newsletters.; Articles.; Posters.; Correspondence.; Pamphlets.; Bumper stickers.; Irish Northern Aid Committee; Irish Action Committee; Irish American Unity Conference; Sinn Fein the Workers' Party; Irish Republican Socialist Party; Sinn Fein; Irish Republican Clubs; Irish Republican Army; McAliskey, Bernadette Devlin, 1947-; McAliskey, Roisin; Prendiville, Sean
- Series I. General Files, 1956-2008
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I contains files on individuals, organizations and various topics related to Irish American activities and responses to events in Northern Ireland. Also included is material on cultural events and organizations in the Northern Californian region.
  - American Committee for Sean O'Casey Centenary, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Irish Historical Society (New York), 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Irish Political Education Committee (AIPEC): MacBride Principles, 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American I.R.A. (California), undated (Box 1, Folder 3A)
  - American Protestants for Truth About Ireland (APTI) I, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Protestants for Truth About Ireland (APTI) II, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Amnesty International I, 1978-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Amnesty International II, 1978-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians (AOH) I, 1987-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians (AOH) II, 1987-1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anti-Catholic Bias - Northern Ireland, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ard Fheis, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ard Fheis, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ard Fheis 5th Annual Convention, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ard Fheis, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ard Fheis, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ard Fheis, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ard Fheis: Election, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Articles and Announcements, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bay Area Irish Cultural Activities, 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bay Area Solidarity Activity, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Beechmount Three, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Belfast Pogrom, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Better Life for All Campaign, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Better Life for All Campaign Support Committee (San Francisco), 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bloody Sunday Exhibit: "Hidden Truths" (San Francisco), 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bodenstown, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Boston 3, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - British Anti-War Movement (N. Ireland), 1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - British Withdrawal from Northern Ireland Campaign (BWNIC), 1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Cabhair (Irish Republican Prisoners and Dependents Aid and Rehabilitation Committee), 1976-1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Campus Friends of Northern Ireland, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Cassin, Denis, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Celtic Foundation, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Censorship, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Children's Artwork, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Citizens for Irish Justice (and other early 1960s support groups), undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Committee for Information on Ireland, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Communist Party of Ireland (includes Manifesto), 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Cosgrove, Liam (Taoiseach; visit to United States), Mar 1976 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Crying Game (motion picture), 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Cumann Citeartha Agus Staire / Culture, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - DeBurca, Mairin: Biographical Information; Visit, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Discussion Papers: Ireland, 1964-1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Doherty, Joe: Brief for the Petitioner (deportation), Oct 27, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Doherty, Joe: National Committee for Joe Doherty, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Drumm, Maire: Newspaper clippings on, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Easter Statements, 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Ellis, Dessie (extradition), 1990, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Emergency Legislation (Ireland), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Emergency Legislation: Newspaper Clippings (Ireland), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Farmers Defense Association, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fitzgerald, Garrett, Minister for Foreign Affairs, Ireland: Speech at Commonwealth Club, San Francisco, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Fliers and Announcements, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Forums, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Fraternal Organizations in Ireland, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Free Bernie McDonagh Committee, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Free Ireland Bookclub (CA), circa 1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Friends of Ireland (Los Angeles), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Friends of Irish Freedom, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Gaelic League, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Gasyard Wall Development Project, Derry City (NI), 1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Gibraltor Shootings, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Grand Jury Defence, circa 1972 (Box Shared Tamiment 157, Folder 16)
  - Haughey, Charles (newspaper clippings), 1976 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - H-Block 4 / H-Block Defense Committee I, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - H-Block 4 / H-Block Defense Committee I, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - H-Block 4 / H-Block Defense Committee / Brennan, Pol, 1994-2008, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Heffernan, Tony, Joint General Secretary, Sinn Fein: United States Speaking Tour, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Hidden Agenda, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - History and Timeline: Economic Subjugation of Ireland, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "HMC Business" (Human Rights Committee), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Human Rights / Pat Finucane Centre, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Hunger Strike, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "In the Cause of Ireland" (article, mock-up), circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility (New York), 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Internment, 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Internment, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Internment Packet (Chronology, background), 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Institute of Celtic Studies: Calendar of Events and By-Laws I, 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Institute of Celtic Studies: Calendar of Events and By-Laws II, 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Ireland Fund, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Ireland: Natural Resources, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Irish Against the War (Iraq), 2007 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Irish American Action Association, 1972-1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Irish American Caucus Democratic Party, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Irish American Labor, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Irish American Support for Irish Struggle: Paper, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Irish American Unity Conference (IAUC) I, 1985-1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Irish American Unity Conference (IAUC) I, 1985-1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Irish American Unity Conference (IAUC): Conference (Los Angeles), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Irish Anarchists, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Irish Arts Festival, 1993-1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Irish Arts Foundation / Gaelforce, 1994, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Irish Community Support Committee, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Irish Council for Civil Rights, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Irish Cultural Society (Mountain View, CA), 1995-1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Irish Democrat Book Centre (book order), 1976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Irish Fair / Ancient Order of Hibernians (Los Angeles), 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Irish Fairs: California, 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Irish Film (articles), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Irish Forum, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Irish Immigration Reform Movement, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Irish and Irish American Memorials, 1987-1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Irish Language, 1989-1993 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Irish Language and Lessons, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Irish Mexican Association of Saint Patrick - San Patricio Battalian 1847 War I, 1992-2001 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Irish Mexican Association of Saint Patrick - San Patricio Battalian 1847 War II, 1992-2001 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Irish National Caucus: Washington D.C., 1975-1984 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Irish Network (various articles), 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Irish Northern Aid Committee: Dublin Bombing (see also NORAID), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Irish Northern Aid Committee: San Francisco I (see also NORAID), 1983-2004 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Irish Northern Aid Committee: San Francisco II (see also NORAID), 1983-2004 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Irish Northern Aid Committee: Testimonial Dinner/Dance (San Francisco) (see also NORAID), 1995 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Irish Northern Aid Committee: "Old" (see also NORAID), 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Irish Political Prisoners Children's Holiday (IPPCH), 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Irish Republican Army (IRA), 1956-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Irish Republican Socialist Committee (IRSC)(San Francisco), 1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Irish Republican Socialist Committee (IRSC), 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Irish Republican Socialist Committee: H-Block, 1980-1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Irish Republican Socialist Party (IRSP): General, articles, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Irish Republican Socialist Party: Press Release Sinn Fein, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Irish Republican Spokespersons in the United States, 1975-1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Irish Struggle": slide show text with slides (Liam Mellows IRC Philadelphia), undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Irish Unity Conference, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Irish World Citizen Organization (genealogy), undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Jenkinson, Noel: Political Prisoner (Irish Prisoners Aid Committee), 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - John Maher Democratic Club, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Johnston, Roy (newspaper article), 1972 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Justice Campaign for Irish Prisoners Abroad, 1969-1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Kelleher, Derry: Publication "An Open Letter to Ian Paisley", 1992 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - KPFA Berkeley (Radio), 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - KQED San Francisco (Radio), 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Labor Day Forum - Irish Politics (Boston), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Leaflets: Originals (see also oversize material), 1977, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Lobbying: Sacramento, 1983-1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Loyalist Propaganda, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Lynch, Larry: Traditional Irish Dancer, 1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - MacBride Principles, 1989-1994 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Macbride Principles: Articles, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Macbride Principles: California I, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Macbride Principles: California II, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Macbride Principles: California III, 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Macbride Principles: California Campaign I, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Macbride Principles: California Campaign II, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Macbride Principles: General Articles, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Macbride Principles: Irish National Caucus, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Macbride Principles: Opposition, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Macbride Principles: Political Education Committee / Emergency Action Request Program (PEC/EARP), 1987 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Macbride Principles: Public Employees Retirement System, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Macbride Principles: San Francisco, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - MacGiolla, Tomas - President, Sinn Fein, 1975-1981 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Malone Defense Fund, 1990-1994 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Mason, Roy, Northern Secretary of State, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Matthews, Chris (includes pamphlet "An Egg Like Me"), 1979-2008 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - McAliskey, Bernadette Devlin [Devlin, Bernadette], 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - McAliskey, Bernadette Devlin [Devlin, Bernadette]: Paper "The Early Life of Bernadette Devlin and the Northern Irisih Civil Rights Movement by Anne Maloney, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - McAliskey, Bernadette Devlin I, 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - McAliskey, Bernadette Devlin II, 1990-1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - McAliskey, Roisin, [1998?] undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - McCormick, Tim, 1977-1980, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - McDermott, Elish, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Meisel, Robert K: Correspondence to Sean Prendiville re: Grand Jury, Butte MT gun-running, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Moriarty, Fr. Cuchulain, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Murray, Marie and Noel (death sentence protest), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Na Fianna Eireann (Youth Movement ), 1974-1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Na Fianna Eireann (Youth Movement), 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - National Council for Civil Liberties (London), 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - New College of California: Irish Studies (Dan Cassidy), 1997-1998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - NORAID and Other Groups I, 1990-1998 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - NORAID and Other Groups II, 1990-1998 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - NORAID and Other Groups: NORAID Annual Meeting (New York), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Northern Ireland: Articles I, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Northern Ireland: Articles II, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Northern Ireland: Articles I, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Northern Ireland: Articles II, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Northern Ireland: Articles III, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Northern Ireland Civil Rights Association (NICRA), 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Northern Ireland Civil Rights Association (NICRA), undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Northern Ireland Civil Rights Association / National Association for Irish Freedom (NICRA / NAIF), 1973-1977 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Northern Ireland Human Rights Commission / Betsy Swart articles, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - O'Brien, Conor Cruise (newspaper clippings), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - O'Conaill, Daithi, Vice-President, Sinn Fein (newspaper articles), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 27A)
  - O'Hare, Majella, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - O'Higgins, Brian, Nov 1968 (Box 5, Folder 28A)
  - Oliver Kearney Family Fund, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - O'Murchu, Eoin, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - O'Riordan, Michael - General Secretary, Communist Party of Ireland, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Peace Movement (Belfast), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Peace Process, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - People's Democracy, 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Photographs (Macbride?), undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Plough and Stars, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Prince Charlie's U.S. / Bay Area Visit [Prince Charles], Oct 1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Princess Margaret Visit (Pig remark in Chicago), 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Prisoners: Correspondence, Cabhair, circa 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Prisoners Rights Organization (Co. Ireland); includes publication Jail Journal, Nos. 5, 7, 11, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Project Children (Children of Northern Ireland), 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Provo: General I (Provisional Irish Republican Army), 1974-1993 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Provo: General II, 1974-1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Provo Split: Status of Provo, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Provo Support (articles, fundraisers), 1984-1998 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Provies (Provos): History, Background, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Reagan / Queen Protest (President Ronald Reagan; Queen Elizabeth II), 1983 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Repsol Publications Catalog (Studies in Irish Politics; see also Series III for Repsol pamphlets), 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Republican Sinn Fein, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Republican Prisoners Long Kesh Co-op Catalog, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Revisionism, 1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Rooney, Eddie, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - San Diego Organizations, 1975-1980 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - San Francisco Irish Film Society I, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - San Francisco Irish Film Society II, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - San Francisco Irish Film Society I, 1993-1996 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - San Francisco Irish Film Society II, 1993-1996 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - San Francisco Irish Film Society, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Seattle's Irish Civil Rights Association, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Sinn Fein: Pamphlets and Fliers (early 19th century), undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Sinn Fein Workers Party (SFWP), 1977-1982 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Sinn Fein Workers Party (SFWP): Correspondence (to Irish Republican Clubs, CA), 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Sinn Fein Workers Party (SFWP): Education Programme, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Sinn Fein Workers Party (SFWP): International Affairs Bureau, 1977-1981 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Sinn Fein Workers Party (SFWP): National Affairs Bureau, 1976-1978 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Sinn Fein Workers Party (SFWP): New Members Class, 1977-1987 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Sinn Fein Workers Party (SFWP): Publications, Programs, 1977-1979, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Sinn Fein Workers Party (SFWP): Statements (Press Releases), 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Songs, 1960, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Starry Plough / La Pena / Plough and Stars, 1980, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Theatre, 1990-1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Thesis: "A Pox and a Curse on the People 'Round Here" by Peter Holland, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Trots" (Trotskyists): Articles, 1975-1978, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Ulster Gaelic Club (San Francisco), 1990-1996 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Union of Students in Ireland / Irish Democratic Youth Movements, 1976-1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - United Irish Societies, 1990-1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Workers Party of Ireland, 1976-1987 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Workers Party Split, 1982-1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Youth (movements), 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Series II. Irish Republican Clubs, 1969-1988
  This series contains files on various Irish Republican Clubs and their activities in Northern California and across the United States. Several folders document activities and work of the national IRC of North America. IRC publications are included in this series.
  - Anne Devlin Club (San Francisco), 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Anne Devlin Club (San Francisco), 1977 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Anne Devlin Club (San Francisco): Correspondence - General and Incoming I, 1969-1980 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Anne Devlin Club (San Francisco): Correspondence - General and Incoming II, 1969-1980 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Anne Devlin Club (San Francisco): Meeting Agendas and Notes, 1975- (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Anne Devlin Club (San Francisco): Meeting Agendas and Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Anne Devlin Club (San Francisco): Meeting Agendas and Notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Bay Area Clubs, 1973-1981 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Bay Area Clubs: Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Bay Area Clubs: Regional Conferences, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Bay Area Clubs: Regional Meetings, 1972-1977 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Benefits: Plough and Stars, Starry Plough, La Pena, 1977-1982 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Boston: Kevin Joyce Correspondence, 1974-1983 (Box 7, Folder 26)